# **Curriculum Vitae**

#### **Personal Information**

Name: Gábor Forgács

Telephone: +36-70-949-949-8 Email: <u>forgacsg@gmail.com</u>

no forgacsg.github.io



## Summary

I am a problem solver with excellent speaking and writing skills. I am able to work on my own initiative as well as part of a team to achieve the best results possible. Through my teaching experience I had the opportunity to engage with several IT teams in organizations of different sizes as well as explore a wide variety of topics in the life of business. During my academic career I felt the desire to pick up technical skills to support my research (mining natural language text for argumentative structures), which led to an increasing interest in the field of data science. I also have had an interest in web development for quite some time and I completed an online bootcamp during the summer of 2020.

### **Relevant Skills**

- Python: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
  Scikit-Learn, Flask, Plotly, Dash
- R: dplyr, ggplot2, tidyverse, R Shiny
- Javascript: MERN stack, D3.js
- SQL: T-SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- NoSQL: MongoDB
- Docker

- Gi
- Dashboarding tools: Power BI | Tableau | Qlik
- GIS: Leaflet, QGIS, Spatial Databases (PostGIS)
- Advanced MS Excel
- MS Office (Word, Powerpoint, Visio)

# **Work Experience**

## 2019 – Senior Data Analyst

British Telecom ROC.

- Analysis of ticket data from various service desk systems
- Data modelling and predictions with Python using ScikitLearn & other packages
- Building API's with Flask
- Dashboard development in Qlik and Python (Dash)
- Deployment with Docker and GitLab CI

## 2017 – 2019: IT Business Analyst

Cushman & Wakefield

- ETL of client data in Python and SQL Server
- Developing dashboards and reports in PowerBI and Tableau
- Historical Payment Reconciliation for key clients based on generated cash-flow in SQL Server

## 2016 – 2017: **System Analyst**

Cushman & Wakefield

- Responsible for Global Occupier Metrics, a webtool for benchmarking real-estate portfolios
- Ensuring data quality for benchmarking
- Reporting user activity trends, benchmarking data pool contents on a quarterly basis
- Project coordination with external developers

## 2012 – 2016: English Language Teacher

Tudomány Language School

References: Ericsson, Ixenit, Bayer, British American Tobacco, Deloitte

### 2014 – 2015: Junior Research Fellow

Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Department of History and

Philosophy of Science

## 2009 – 2011: English Language Teacher

Institution for the Education of Insurance Studies

### **Education**

2017 – 2018: Microsoft Professional Program in Data Science

2011 – 2014: Graduate student at the Budapest University of Technology and Economics,

Department of History and Philosophy of Science

2009: Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (University of Pécs)

2009: Master of Arts in Teaching Philosophy (University of Pécs)

## **Online Course Certificates**

• Udemy: The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

• Coursera: Foundations of Business Strategy

Coursera: Competitive Strategy

• EdX: Networks, Crowds and Markets

Coursera: Logic: Language and Information 2

## **Awards, Honours and Memberships**

2009: Second Place at the XXIX. Biannual National Scholarly Competition for Students – in

the category of English Theoretical and Descriptive Linguistics

2008: CEEPUS research scholarship at the Karl Franzens Universität, Graz

2005 – 2009: member of the University of Pécs Kerényi Károly Extracurricular Study Fraternity,

Senior in 2007-2008

## **Language Proficiency**

English
 C2 - Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (2009)

German B2 TELC intermediate exam, type "C"